avaya.com 2016-06-24

# Privacy Statement

Your privacy is important to Avaya!

This statement discloses how Avaya Inc. (4655 Great America Parkway, Santa Clara, CA 95054-1233, USA ) and its worldwide affiliates (collectively "Avaya") process personal information about individuals (“Personal Data”), including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared.

###  Scope of Privacy Statement

This statement also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal data and how you can access and update this information. This privacy statement only covers the website www.avaya.com and pages linking from our website in the Careers section that are hosted on our third party service provider’s URL. 

###  TRUSTe

Avaya has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy statement or practices, please contact us at executiveoffice@avaya.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request> . The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this site and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from our site or mobile applications. 

###  Collection and Use of Personal Data

Avaya has long recognized that individuals with whom we conduct business value their privacy. However, in order to conduct global business in this increasingly electronic economy, the collection and Use of Personal Data is often necessary and desirable for businesses and individuals involved. It is Avaya's goal to balance the benefits of our and our customers’ business with the right of individuals to prevent the misuse of their Personal Data. Avaya aims to collect as little information as possible to protect these individuals’ Personal Data.

###  Data Retention

We will retain and use your information (Personal Data) (i) for as long as your account is active, (ii) as needed to provide you services, or (iii) as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

###  International Data Transfer and Safe Harbor

Avaya as a global company and provider of Internet-accessible services needs to transfer Personal Data around the world over public telecommunications networks. As such, data transfers will naturally include territories outside your country, including outside the EU. In addition, worldwide Avaya affiliates report to the company headquarters in the USA which may have access to Personal Data of our customers globally. To ensure such transfers of Personal Data are safeguarded legally, Avaya complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Avaya has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Avaya’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. In addition to Safe Harbor Avaya has in place EU Model Contract Clauses between Avaya’s European Union and US legal entities, to ensure all data exported to the US has adequate levels of protection.

###  Security of Personal Data

  The security of your Personal Data is important to us. Avaya will implement commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures to aid in protecting Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration unauthorized disclosure or access. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the information during transmission. 

###  Transfer of Personal Data

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the Personal Data submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage however is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at [executiveoffice@avaya.com](mailto:executiveoffice@avaya.com) . 

###  Disclosure to Third Parties / Sharing of Personal Data / Subcontracting

In order to provide you with products and services, we may enter into contractual relationships with third parties such as vendors, suppliers, business partners, service providers, and other contractors (“Contractors”). Please be assured that we select these subcontractors with the greatest possible care. In addition, subcontractors will be contractually bound to Avaya’s security standards and guidelines regarding the handling of your Personal Data. When using Contractors we may share parts of your Personal Data with these companies. However, we only disclose information which is required to carry out their task. Avaya reserves the right to exercise control over the information at all times in order to protect your Personal Data. In all instances in which we disclose or share your Personal Data with others we comply with all legal regulations applicable in the specific case. We may also disclose your Personal Data 1) as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process; 2) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, your safety, or the safety of others; 3) to investigate fraud; 4) to respond to a government request; or 5) if Avaya is involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of all or a portion of its assets. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website(s) of any changes in ownership, uses of your Personal Data, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Data. 

###  Data Breach

We employ data protection standards with a view to protecting our customers' Personal Data.

Depending on the jurisdiction applicable, we are obliged by law to inform you about severe breaches of security in our IT network which affect your Personal Data. Where legally required we will notify you personally where possible and display a notice on our website in case of such a breach. 

###  Policy Update Procedure

Regarding future features or products offered by Avaya which might affect your Personal Data we reserve the right to amend or change this Privacy Statement accordingly. A notice will be displayed on our website after any such change happened. If we make any material changes to this privacy statement, we will notify you by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. 

###  Privacy Officer and Feedback

For all feedback, concerns or suggestions regarding Avaya, please contact us at:  
Avaya Data Privacy Office (Avaya Law), Postal Address: Avaya Inc. 4655 Great America Parkway, Santa Clara, CA 95054,  
Email: [executiveoffice@avaya.com](mailto:executiveoffice@avaya.com),

Web site URL: <http://www.avaya.com/usa/contact/email-avaya/>.

For all other inquiries regarding Avaya’s Privacy Statement and your rights in this regard, you can contact our Global Privacy Officer Joerg Thomas, who may be reached at  
[dataprivacy@avaya.com](mailto:dataprivacy@avaya.com). 

###  Forums / Chat Rooms

If you participate in Avaya -run forums or contact our support service via a chat service, online interface or email, we will ask you for additional Personal Data such as a forum moniker, the hardware you are using or the technical issue you are experiencing. Avaya stores your content to run the forums and chat rooms and to process your query. Please note that content you post in public forums and chat rooms is open for anyone to see.

###  Linked Websites

Avaya includes selected links to Avaya websites and external websites. Although Avaya checks the content of external websites before linking to them, we do not have any authority about these website operators. Avaya is therefore not responsible for the content of external links.

###  Third Party/Products/Software, SnapIns

With some Avaya products you may use third-party products and services such as snap-ins and other software that is not provided by us. Please refer to the third parties’ documentation and websites for information about their privacy practices.

###  Notice and Choice Principle

Most of Avaya’s websites are available and open to you without having to provide any Personal Data. However, in order to access and use certain Avaya websites or parts of websites, we may request Personal Data from you, like your name, e-mail address, company name and telephone number. If you do not submit the requested Personal Data, you may not have access to certain Avaya websites or parts of websites.

###  Cookies and Tracking Software

**Avaya**

Some websites of Avaya use tracking technologies such as cookies, scripts and tags. "Cookies" are small files that the website places on your computer’s hard drive and/or internet browser for identification purposes. Cookies are used to better serve you when you return to the website which has implemented it. You should note that cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive. Your web browser may allow you to be notified when you are receiving a cookie, giving you the choice to accept it or not. By not accepting cookies, some pages may not fully function and you may not be able to access certain information on Avaya websites.

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies to display content based upon what you view on our website to personalize your visit. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and way data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for cookies click here <http://www.avaya.com/usa/cookiepolicy>.

Avaya also collects domain information (e.g. IP address and referring URLs) as part of its analysis of the use of this website. This data enables us to become more familiar with which customers visit our website, how often they visit and what parts of the website they visit most often. Avaya uses this information to improve its web-based offerings. This information is collected automatically and requires no action on your part. We do not tie Personal Data to domain information, except where it is necessary to prevent abuse or fraud on our website.

**Third parties**

Some of our business partners (e.g., tracking utility services) may use cookies, script, tags, local storage and web beacons on our website. Our third party tracking utility services company uses a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our website by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on websites and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. These clear gifs are not tied to our customers' Personal Data. Local storage (HTML5) are used to provide certain features on our websites, to display advertising based on your web browsing activities, and to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

We partner with a third party ad network to display advertising on our website and to manage our advertising on other websites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>. If you are located in the European Union, click here [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) . Please note this does not prevent you from being shown advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**DNT**

We recognize that some people use so called “Do Not Track” cookies while being online in order to prevent websites from collecting the data they leave on the websites and therefore prevent them from tracking their online behavior. Avaya treats the use of these cookies as if no consent was given for the use of cookies on the website. In such cases it may be possible that we cannot provide you with access to certain secure parts of the website(s). 

###  Analytics tools

**Google Analytics**

Website of Avaya may use Google Analytics, a service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). This service uses cookies to help Avaya analyze how visitors use the website. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website (including your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google, including outside the EU in third countries such as the USA, which might not have data protection laws as comprehensive as in your country.

On this website, IP anonymization has been activated so that your IP address is truncated beforehand within the EU. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to Google’s non-EU servers and truncated there. Google uses the information on Avaya’s behalf for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website and compiling reports on website activity. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by them.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; for instructions on how to do this please visit the browser manufacturers’ website. Alternatively, you can download and install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on available via <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. More information about privacy in connection with Google Analytics can be found at <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>.

**Webtrends Analytics**

Website of Avaya may use Webtrends Analytics provided by Webtrends Inc. (555 SW Oak Street, Suite 300, Portland, Oregon, 97204, USA). This service uses cookies to help Avaya analyze how visitors use the site. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website (including your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Webtrends, including outside the EU in third countries such as the USA, which might not have data protection laws as comprehensive as in your country..

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; for instructions on how to do this please visit the browser manufacturers’ website.

###  User's Rights

You have the right to refuse to provide Personal Data to us. However, in such cases we cannot provide you with access to certain secure parts of the website(s).

In the course of registering on the Avaya website, you have been asked to consent to the use, transfer, export and retention of your Personal Data as set out in this Privacy Statement. Consequently, after registering, Avaya may use this submitted information for the purposes for which you and Avaya have intended, including the provision of additional information, such as alerting you to products and services that can assist you in your business, promoting website registration, and assisting in order processing.

Depending on the jurisdiction applicable, you may have a legal right to a copy of all the Personal Data stored about you by Avaya. If you wish to obtain a copy of particular information provided to Avaya or if you become aware that the information stored by Avaya is incorrect and you would like Avaya to correct or delete it, please contact us at executiveoffice@avaya.com.

At any time you have the right to withdraw your consent to the use of your Personal Data by sending an e-mail to [executiveoffice@avaya.com](mailto:executiveoffice@avaya.com). We will respond to your request as soon as possible.

###  Children's Rights

Avaya is sensitive to the protection of the interests of children. To the extent we are aware that a child is communicating with us, we will respond to such e-mails, but we do not store the names, addresses or e-mails themselves in our databases, nor do we share them with third parties other than for fulfillment services. At the same time we believe that parents have the ultimate responsibility to supervise their children's online activities. We urge parents to discuss the online release and protection of personal information with their children. Whenever we request personally identifiable information from a child, we will also ask for a parent's e-mail address so that we can notify the parent that we have received personal information from the child. Parents have the right to review any personal information we have collected from their child by following the procedures for data access set out in the “User’s rights” section. 

###  Social Media

Links to the social network Facebook (operated by Facebook, Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA for users living in the USA or Canada; Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland for users living in other parts of the world ) are integrated in our websites. Links to Facebook are clearly highlighted on our website by using the Facebook logo or through the plug-in “Like” button. 

Facebook’s plug-in is activated when clicking on the Facebook link. Following the activation of Facebook’s plug-in, your browser will establish a connection with the Facebook servers. In the event your Facebook account, if any, is activated, the fact that you have visited our websites will be shared with Facebook. Facebook will assign your visit on our website to your Facebook account.

The operation of Facebook links requires activation by you. An automatic transfer of information to Facebook does not happen.

Please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy (<https://www.facebook.com/policy.php> ) for more information in this context.

###  Feedback Reporting

Avaya aims at providing the best possible services to its customers. Part of achieving this goal is our dedicated customer care service. All the incidents being reported through the various channels by which you can reach the customer care service are recorded and collected. This way we can use all the questions we are getting from our customers to create better services for them, e.g. by including them in up-to-date FAQs. 

###  Tell a Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website(s) or products, we will ask you for your friend's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the website. Avaya does not store this information and only uses it for the purpose of sending the invitation e-mail. 

In the event Avaya conducts a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a significant portion of its assets, your Personal Data will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified on our Web site of any such change in ownership or control of your Personal Data.

Last updated: February 2016
